

Hansel Esteban Ramos Osorio

Senior Software Developer Systems Engineer - Computer Engineer

PHP Backend Developer MEAN Fullstack Developer



(+57) 310 770-7149 (Whatsapp)



hansell.ramos@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/hansellramos



hansellramos.github.io





about.me/hanselramos

Abstract

I'm a software developer and I love it, makes me happy contribute to improve the process on the people, companies, make it more efficient, save cost, time and energy because at the end it reflects on people life quality. My favorite project are those that impacts on people day to day since simple things like pets or children to employee or transportation

Graduates as an engineer about in 2010 and have worked as a developer even some years before tha, I've specialized as a web developer and my favorite technologies are PHP and Angular and I passionate by project involved on mobile applications because generally are that makes easier people life.

I have lived in different cities and countries and shared with partners from around the world those experiences have been valuable to me because they allowed to me work with different cultures and enrich my experience and perspectives around teamwork.

Languages





Spanish - Native

English - B1



Passport with American Visa B1/B2

Main Skills

Backend

PHP



Codeigniter, Symfony, Laravel, Lumen, CakePHP

Frontend

Angular



HTML, CSS, jQuery, SCSS, Less

Databases







Oracle, Sql Server, PostgreSQL

Experience Summary

- +12 years of experience as Web Developer.
 - +5 years working with mobile application on backend side.
- +3 years working with integrations systems.

Worked with renowned companies like Disney, Universal Studios, Johnson & Johnson, Globant.

Complementary Skills

Programming Languages

- Javascript Nodeis, Golang, Java, Android (In progress), iOS (In Progress) Devops
 - AWS, Google Cloud, Docker, Kubernetes, Heroku, CI (Continuous Integration)

Mobile Technologies

Ionic, iOS (in course), Android (in course), Arduino

Other Knowledge

• UI/UX Design, Business Intelligence

CRM - Inventory Systems

Oracle Netsuite, YellowDog

Personal Information



Residence in Barranguilla, Atlántico, Colombia



Born May 29, 1989 (31 years old) in Barranguilla, Colombia



Married to Mailen



Father of Norelkys (8 years old), Esteban and Jade (5 years old), Mayha (3 Years Old)

Employment History



Avantica Technologies Encora



Oct 2018 - Aug 2020 1 year 10 months



Barranquilla - Colombia San Carlos - Costa Rica Lima - Perú

Senior Software Engineer

- Backend Developer for POS software (Appetize) used on Disney Stores, Stadiums and massive public events.
- Integrations backend developer for same POS software integrating different inventory and CRM like Oracle Netsuite, Yellowdog and Disney internal systems.

Technologies

PHP, Codeigniter, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS DynamoDB, Oracle Netsuite, Yellowdog.



Globant



Nov 2016 - Oct 2018 1 year 11 months



Medellín - Colombia

Senior PHP Developer

- Backend developer for Johnson & Johnson mobile application for post-surgery self care.
- Full Stack developer for Universal Studios web media content distribution platform.
- Backend developer for Hallmark Channel proxy application between VOD platform and end users.
- Sustainment of Disneyland Resorts, Disney World Parks and Disney Cruise Line Reservations portal to Disney.

Technologies

PHP, Codeigniter, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS DynamoDB.



Yuxi Global Latam



Jan 2016 - Sep 2016 8 Months



Medellín - Colombia

Senior PHP Developer

• Update system used for **CDI Tech** used on its human resources process from old Dojo technologies to jQuery.

Technologies

PHP, HTML5, MySQL, Javascript, Jquery, Dojo.



Todosistemas S.T.I. Alpopular S.A.



Apr 2015 - Dec 2015 8 Months



Bogotá - Colombia

Developer Engineer

 Development of document management system named Kompendium for file logistics warehouses and customers of the organization.

Technologies

PHP, Symfony 1 and 2, HTML5, Mysql.

Tel: (+57) 310 770-7149 - Mail: hansell.ramos@gmail.com



Linktic



Sep 2014 - Mar 2015 9 Months



Bogotá - Colombia

PHP Developer

- Implemented and personalized LMS for University by Ministry of Justice-Prosecution.
- Implemented and personalized a web platform based on Joomla for students management for the university.
- Developed a web application to schedule medical appointments for telemedicine on Bolivar Government.
- Developed backend of application used for mini-stores on neighborhoods for La Guajira Government and Meta Government.

Technologies

PHP, CakePHP, MySQL, HTML5, jQuery, Moodle, Joomla, AWS EC2, AWS RDS.



Neotech Engineering



May 2014 - July 2014 3 Months (Project)



Bogotá - Colombia

Development Engineer

• Development and update of a web-based java software to generate reports in the superintendence of the Economy.

Technologies

Java, JSP, PL/SQL, Oracle.



Bision Consulting



Feb 2014 - Apr 2014 3 Months (Project)



Bogotá - Colombia

BI Consultant

 Provided advice and implemented Business Intelligence solution for Toys R Us stores on Spain.

Technologies

BI, ETL, IBM Cognos.



Universidad Autónoma del Caribe



Apr 2011 - Dec 2013 2 years 8 Months



Barranquilla - Colombia

Support Engineer

- Developed a solution for supervising students use and behavior of university computers room on windows and Mac operating systems.
- Developed a ETL solution to synchronize AS400 database with LMS platform.
- Implemented and personalized Moodle LMS platform.
- Designed and developed an application to manage room computers class schedule and reservations.
- Implemented a load balancing service of Mysql and apache to improve availability of academic systems.

Technologies

PHP, Moodle, ETL, Java, Javascript, jQuery, JSP, C#, MySQL, SQL Server, AS400, NBL, Apache.

Tel: (+57) 310 770-7149 - Mail: hansell.ramos@gmail.com



Meisa - Cajacopi



Dec 2010 - Feb 2011 3 Months



Barranquilla - Colombia

Level I Developer

 Designed and developed a solution for scheduling meetings, events rooms of the company.

Technologies

ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server, Windows Server.



Universidad Autónoma del Caribe



Mar 2010 - Sep 2010 6 Months (passant)



Barranquilla - Colombia

Development Passant

- Configured a VmWare cluster to implement academic systems.
- Configured an active directory synchronization with AS400 database.
- Designed a solution for computer class rooms schedules and reservations.
- Designed an ETL process to synchronize AS400 database with MySQL.

Technologies

PHP, Moodle, ETL, Java, Javascript, jQuery, JSP, C#, MySQL, SQL Server, AS400, NBL, Apache.



Innova Group International



Jan 2008 - Dec 2008 1 Year



Barranquilla - Colombia

Web Master

Designed and developed web pages for different customers.

Technologies

PHP, HTML5, Flash, MySQL.

Freelance Experience



Parrot Labs Inc.



Medellín - Colombia

• Fixed some bugs in a web application developed to a Healthy company, based on PHP and used to statistic measures and analysis.

Technologies

PHP, Restful Services, MySQL.



Maynard - USA

Updated for didactical games developed on Flash, this games was re-developed on Javascript using different frameworks like PixiJS and PandaJS.

Technologies

Javascript, Pixi.JS, PandaJS, Webpack, Restful Services.

Tel: (+57) 310 770-7149 - Mail: hansell.ramos@gmail.com



Productos Químicos Panamericanos S.A.



Barranquilla - Colombia

 Designed and developed a web application used for quality control system in the company.

Technologies

AngularJS, Nodejs, ExpressJS, MongoDB, ETL, Bootstrap, Material Design.



Fenix Web Agency.



Bucaramanga - Colombia

 Designed and develop a games-oriented application based on mentally challenges between different peoples and friends.

Technologies

PHP, Javascript, Pixi.JS, PandaJS, Webpack, Restful Services, MySQL, Angular, Ionic.

Personal Projects

Rutana



Is a transportation solution to share travels at low cost in association with universities in Barranquilla Colombia.

Trit/Peladera





Is a solution provided to the private sector (Trit) and government (Peladera) to offer services like carpentry, stylist. To connect offert with demand.

Esmimascota.com

Is a solution to provide identification of pets in a central database and share medals that can be wear by those pets.

Oso Loteria

Is a solution during pandemic times to play with family the classic lottery games, I'm developing this specifically to play with my grandma and my aunts that loves these game.

Technologies: PHP, Golang, Mongodb, Firebase, Heroku, Angular, Ionic, Android, iOS.

Education

Systems Engineer - Informatic Engineer

Universidad Autónoma del Caribe

Barranquilla - Colombia 2006 - 2011 License: 08255-298102 ATL (Professional Card-COPNIA)

MongoDB Aggregation Framework MongoDB University

2018

License: b6790dc9-2463-4347-a8fc-d3d7c330



Tel: (+57) 310 770-7149 - Mail: hansell.ramos@gmail.com

References

MAILEN MONTENEGRO Wife Scrum Master – Project Manager Phone: (+57) 300 200-1464	JESÚS MONTENEGRO Brother in law Legal adviser Phone: (+57) 300 637-9135
DAIRY TORRENEGRA Management Systems Analyst Olimpica S.A. Phone: (+57) 300 334 6899	DANIEL MONTOYA Senior Software Developer Naez Phone: (+57) 312 298-2847

I certify that all information contained in this document is true and accurate, and to authorize such data are verified for which provided the necessary data and acquaintances.

Hansel Ramos Osorio C.C. 1'129.523.274 de Barranquilla